Understood, Father.
Your right to succeed the
throne has been restored?
There was no other choice, with Al gone now.
Um, so... This means...
You'll be the next ruler of the kingdom?
I guess so.
The kingdom's never had
a queen in charge, though.
The king's spouse has always
been just a consort...
So I guess I'll have to take
a prince consort eventually.
A prince consort?
I have to pass down
the royal blood, after all.
We've still got the much bigger problem
of getting the nobles to accept me, though!
Even after the right to the throne
has been restored to you?
Yeah...
No matter how far I get, not being
able to use magic holds me back.
I think I can be of some help.
As the daughter of Duke Magenta,
I should be able to serve as an intermediary
between you and the nobles.
That's okay.
This doesn't really have
anything to do with you two.
You can just take it easy.
N-Nothing to do with...
Euphie's my assistant
in magicology research,
and Lainie, I guess you're
a maid-in-training.
This whole issue is totally
separate from any of that.
Well, I'm gonna head to the workshop.
I thought you would argue
against what she just said.
Why is that?
I mean... if Miss Anis
takes a consort... well...
I was...
asked by Prince Algard
to take care of Miss Anis.
I have to support her
as one of her subjects.
I... see...
It's okay. I was prepared for this.
I know I can do it.
I am Anisphia Wynn Palettia,
the only princess in this kingdom.
It can't be helped.
It's okay.
It's okay...
The Magical Revolution
of the Reincarnated Princess and the Genius Young Lady
Honestly, she's such an idiot.
She should just adopt a kid from
some prominent noble family.
Th-There's no need to put it that way...
Are you concerned about
Miss Anis becoming queen?
Huh?
Aren't you the one who should be concerned?
No, not in particular...
Be honest.
I am being honest.
It's only right for me to support
the queen as one of her subjects.
Look—
I'm back!
Er, huh? You're not done with the exam yet?
Hah!
Did you have a nice time
talking to all those nobles?
Oh, uh... I mean, I guess.
I might actually be better
at this than I thought...
kinda?
What is that look on your face?
C-Come on.
Insulting my face is uncalled for.
That card's off-limits.
You know very well that's not what I meant!
I just know what my own face
looks like, that's all.
So long, old me! Say hello to my new normal!
A new you?
I'm Anisphia Wynn Palettia,
the princess who's next
in line for the throne!
Sorry.
Lady Tilty, please, that's enough.
Idiot!
You are such an idiot!
If that's how you're going to be,
don't blame me for whatever happens!
So this is where you've been.
Oh... Sorry about earlier.
I was trying to avoid seeing Tilty
because I knew it'd end up this way.
No, it's...
Don't worry about her.
It's not really fun when she gets mad
at me over my face, though...
I am worried.
Huh?
What Tilty said was completely out of line,
but you two seemed to be on the same page.
O-Oh, yeah!
More importantly, I gotta go
pick up Arc-en-Ciel!
A-Arc-en-Ciel?
I was too hard on it,
so I left it with a blacksmith
in town for maintenance.
Well, see you later!
It's late. You can do that tomorrow.
And I'll be going with you.
Huh?
Your body is not yours alone anymore.
If you wait until something happens,
it'll be too late.
Are you... talking about a date?
Huh?
Just the two of us, sneaking out on a date?
Just us?! What about guards?
If we guard each other, there's no problem!
That's... But...
Come on, Euphie...
Please?
This way, Euphie.
Yes, Miss Anis.
I mean, um... Anis.
Get used to it quick, Euphie!
You're here.
Oh, Tomas. All done with
the weapon I left here?
Of course I am.
Who's she?
My assistant!
Oh...
The one who uses that thing, huh?
Pleasure to meet you. My name is Euphie.
I know who you are. Duke Magenta's daughter.
The fiancée Miss Anis swiped
from Prince Algard, right?
No, no! I didn't swipe her!
We were both in agreement!
It was a completely legal procedure!
I couldn't care less about
what nobles are up to.
Who you see here right now is just Euphie,
so please call me that.
That so? Doesn't sound so bad.
Hang on just a sec.
Pull it out, and check it over.
Um, is something...
My assistant's pretty amazing, isn't she?
Yeah...
I can see why you took a liking to her.
By now, I'm so dependent on Arc-en-Ciel
that I don't feel right without it.
Thank you for your flawless work, Tomas.
Yeah, sure.
Oh! It's the real Miss Anis!
See? I told you!
Miss Anis! I got some nice,
fresh fish in today!
Hey!
Let's finish the game we started last time!
Miss Anis!
Come on, please!
Go on.
I'll just do some final checks on this
and then give it to Euphie.
Sorry! I won't be long!
Come on, take turns!
Tell me one thing.
All right...
Will our next ruler be Miss Anis?
I believe so, yes.
I see.
Are you that uneasy with the idea
of Miss Anis being queen?
I'm not uneasy.
She comes to visit the town
pretty frequently.
There are a lot of folks who
believe she can be trusted.
But you don't seem very happy about it.
Yeah, I'm not.
Why is that?
You have no ide—
Look at all the stuff they gave me!
You can have some of it, Tomas.
Did something happen?
Nope. We're done talking.
Go on home.
Oh...
Thank you.
Has something happened?
Huh?
You've seemed out of sorts
since you returned from town.
I'm just... not sure I understand anymore.
I really believe that Miss Anis
will be a queen
who can bring the nobles and
the commoners together...
Don't you think so, too?
I think she will be a benevolent ruler.
But...
She probably isn't cut out for it.
Having power and being forced
to use it are not the same.
If the princess becomes queen,
she won't be able to go into
town anymore, will she?
Well...
But she has a responsibility,
so I suppose she has no choice...
Come with me, please.
Did Miss Anis do all this?
The princess may act like a wild child
with no concept of good sense,
but at her core, she is a
very conscientious person.
That is true, but...
In order to be a ruler accepted by all,
she will probably never associate
with magicology again.
But that's...
She takes too much upon herself.
That hasn't changed since she was little.
If she becomes queen...
she will most likely throw away
what is precious to her.
But...
I am the daughter of Duke Magenta.
I have my duty as a noble...
as part of a royal household.
Once the princess has fulfilled her duty...
Do you think she will smile happily?
That... That's not...
But... why...
do I...
So...
Not knowing what else to do,
you came all the way here to talk to me?
Yes.
I just... want to help her.
I don't want to see her sad.
It just hurts so much that I can't solve
Miss Anis's problems for her.
"Miss Anis's problems"?
That's your first mistake.
Huh?
This is actually your problem, isn't it?
Mine?
Yes, an issue of your own feelings.
What are you really thinking right now?
Say it.
But... I...
Say it!
It's my duty to support the royal family,
but I personally...
don't want Miss Anis to become queen.
Having your heart at odds with
your duty was painful, wasn't it?
I know this feeling I have is wrong.
What does it matter
whether it's right or wrong?
Just try to find the path
that you truly want to take.
Can I really... have hope?
If that's what you've decided to do,
there's no one who can stop you.
You're the most brilliant genius young lady
in this kingdom, aren't you?
It's unusual for you to visit my office,
Euphie.
There's something I wish
to consult you about.
Oh? That's even more unusual.
Does the kingdom's next ruler
absolutely have to be Miss Anis?
Why do you ask that?
Because I don't want Miss Anis to be queen.
A kingdom is only a kingdom
if it has a monarch.
Princess Anisphia must fulfill her duty
in order to protect this kingdom.
And it's your job to support her.
Am I wrong?
I...
Even so, I cannot accept it.
Why?
Because that is not where
Miss Anis can truly smile!
Smile?
Are you saying that's more important
than our kingdom's future?
This kingdom, and all of its people,
cannot be traded for just one
person's smile. I realize that.
But still...
I don't want to accept it as
just the way things must be!
Is this out of devotion or obligation?
Or is it sympathy?
I just... love her.
Even if I lose my position, my family,
and everything I have,
my feelings won't change.
You truly care that much
for Princess Anisphia?
Yes.
As Duke Magenta,
I cannot, under any circumstances,
accept these misplaced feelings of yours.
I know that.
But while I am fully aware
that it isn't right,
I can no longer...
Long ago, Orphanse loved gardening
more than anyone else.
He even declared that his dream was to
become a common subject and study plants.
He was no less of a problem child
than Princess Anisphia herself.
But he threw away his dream of happiness.
All to stop the nobles' uprising
and become king.
And I supported him with all my strength.
For our kingdom's sake.
However...
The truth is, at that time,
we had another option.
You mean...
Spirits? But why...
I wish you wouldn't show up without notice.
It's been a long time.
You've aged quite a bit, Grantz.
And you don't seem to have changed at all.
What brings you here?
You've already figured it out, haven't you?
Aren't you going to introduce me?
This lady...
is Miss Lumi, a spirit contractor.
Spirit contractor?
Um... Shall I leave you two alone?
Oh, my, no.
I came here to see you, after all.
Huh?
Tell me, Euphyllia...
What does a spirit contract
signify in this kingdom?
Eh? Um...
Forging a contract with a greater spirit
that possesses immense power
signifies one's authority
as a member of the royal family.
From the legend of the founder
and first king of Palettia, yes?
Those who have entered a spirit contract
are capable of starting a new royal dynasty.
Yes...
One could even overtake the
legitimate heir to the throne
and become a new monarch.
You mean...
If I were to enter a spirit contract
and earn the acknowledgment of the nobles,
Miss Anis wouldn't have to become queen?
Don't!
I don't...
Yes.
You declined to enter a contract, Grantz.
You were going to enter a spirit contract?
I met the requirements,
and I didn't want to do it.
That's it.
Why not?
A spirit contract is not the wonderful thing
that the people of this kingdom think it is.
Oh, dear. What an unpleasant
look in your eyes.
I'm very sorry,
but I would do anything to...
Your feelings are that strong?
How very, very cruel.
Miss Lumi?
I came here to stop you.
To make sure the same mistake
wouldn't be repeated.
Let me tell you... a certain story.
Episode Ten
The Royal Succession of Resignation and Fury
Episode Eleven
The Spirit Contract of Despair and Determination